<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Living in the (Brazilian) end times</title>
    <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Living in the (Brazilian) end times</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:08:43 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://augnun.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Lost Leopoldo</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/we-lost-leopoldo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:08:43 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/we-lost-leopoldo/</guid>
      <description>Leopoldo Luque died today from Covid-19 complications.&#xA;Last year the Argentinian journal El Clarín published his chilling account of almost being killed by the Argentinian dictatorship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With Disqus</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/the-problem-with-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 10:52:58 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/the-problem-with-disqus/</guid>
      <description>Recently I saw on Hacker News a very nice blog post about disqus: it always seemed to me like a shady tool, ubiquitous but at the same time leading to some potential privacy risks.&#xA;Supun Kavinda&amp;rsquo;s very nice explanation puts a light to this problem which.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Moved to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/why-i-moved-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 11:13:17 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/why-i-moved-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Well, I was very aggravated by Jekyll, Ruby and all it&amp;rsquo;s dependency management, environment setup etc.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s try using Hugo this time. Maybe I can learn Go and finally kickstart this blogging project.&#xA;Here goes nothing!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organization vs Procastination</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/organization-vs-procastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:55:44 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/organization-vs-procastination/</guid>
      <description>During undergrad school I leaned heavily on Anki. It did a really good job on keeping me up with a few hard to grasp concepts and formulas, while muscling up my memory with many banal stuff in a few harder courses. It was fun, easy and readily actionable, you can get instant feedback on how you&amp;rsquo;re going.&#xA;Even though I loved it, I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched it properly in years. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, but memorizing formulas doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem that valuable anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zizek vs Self: On Dangerous Ideas</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/zizek-vs-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 11:55:30 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/zizek-vs-self/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting debate between the slovenian philosopher Slavoj Zizek and british author Will Self. I think that they present a important (im)balance between academicism and ideology - represented by Zizek&amp;rsquo;s incessant references and hegelianism and an enormous amount of cinicism and pessimism personified by Self.&#xA;I love both authors. Self has written a few books which I found quite enjoyable: Great Apes, How the Dead Live and The Book of Dave alternate between humor which is often dark and twisted, tenderness and societal pessimism.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
