<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://augnun.github.io/xml/base.min.xml" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Living in the (Brazilian) end times</title>
    <link>http://augnun.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Living in the (Brazilian) end times</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 11:55:30 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://augnun.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zizek vs Self: On Dangerous Ideas</title>
      <link>http://augnun.github.io/posts/zizek-vs-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 11:55:30 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://augnun.github.io/posts/zizek-vs-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting debate between the slovenian philosopher Slavoj Zizek and british author Will Self. I think that they present a important (im)balance between academicism and ideology - represented by Zizek&amp;rsquo;s incessant references and hegelianism and an enormous amount of cinicism and pessimism personified by Self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love both authors. Self has written a few books which I found quite enjoyable: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarything.com/work/28486&#34;&gt;Great Apes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarything.com/work/2451396&#34;&gt;How the Dead Live&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarything.com/work/752948&#34;&gt;The Book of Dave&lt;/a&gt; alternate between humor which is often dark and twisted, tenderness and societal pessimism. His presentation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychogeography&#34;&gt;Psychogeography&lt;/a&gt; is provoking, albeit without much of the revolutionary &lt;em&gt;élan&lt;/em&gt; enforced originally by Debord &lt;em&gt;et caterva&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zizek has written one of my favorite books: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarything.com/work/8998398&#34;&gt;First as Tragedy, Then as Farce&lt;/a&gt;. Zizek has wit, revolutionary edge and enough political baggage to present a very compelling argument in favor of his flavor of Communism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always: don&amp;rsquo;t read the video comments. People have greatly misunderstood the interaction between them: they think Self is childish and narcisistic, but he is merely presenting himself as a staunch cynic, pessimist and skeptical of revolutionary action. I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly agree with him specifically in the last point, but I think he presents this sincerely and must be recognized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CId1iOWQUuo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
